<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Budaspest Guide</string>
    <string name="landmarks_fragment_name">Landmarks</string>
    <string name="landmarks_description">Budapest is an old city, full of beautiful art, architecture, and monuments.  Listed here are a few of the most iconic sights of the city.</string>
    <string name="bridges_fragment_name">Bridges</string>
    <string name="bridges_description">There are over a dozen bridges that cross the Danube River in the Budapest era, most dating back to the 19th or early 20th century.  Unfortunately, all the bridges were partially destroyed during World War II, when the retreating German army broke them to slow the Russian advance.  One by one, however, these beautiful spans were rebuilt, giving Budapest the iconic look of a river city.</string>
    <string name="museums_fragment_name">Museums</string>
    <string name="museums_description">Budapest is home to many fine art, history, and science museums, which display collections from around the world but, of course, specialize in Hungarian art and historical artifacts.</string>
    <string name="music_fragment_name">Music</string>
    <string name="music_description">While Vienna may have been home to Mozart and Beethoven, there is a rich history of music and music patronage in Budapest.  This is alive today in the form of many splendid concert spaces and classical music ensembles.</string>
    <string name="basilica_name">St. Stephen\'s Basilica</string>
    <string name="basilica_description">St. Stephen\'s Basilica (Hun. <i>Szent István-Bazilika</i>) is a neoclassical Catholic basilica completed in 1905, named after Saint Stephen, the first king of Hungary.  It dominates the landscape in the heart of Pest, and is one of the most recognizable buildings in the city.</string>
    <string name="parliament_name">Parliament Building</string>
    <string name="parliament_description">The Hungarian Parliament Building (Hun. <i>Országház</i>) is the most striking structure on the banks of the Danube in Budapest, finished in 1904, shortly after the millennial anniversary of Hungary.  This sprawling neo-Gothic complex is still the meeting place of the Hungarian National Assembly, and it houses the no-longer-used crown jewels of Hungary.</string>
    <string name="chain_bridge_name">Chain Bridge</string>
    <string name="chain_bridge_description">The Chain Bridge (Hun. <i>Széchenyi Lánchíd</i>) is an iron and stone suspension bridge built in the mid-19th century to cross the Danube, connecting the hearts of Buda and Pest, the eastern and western halves of Budapest.</string>
    <string name="liberty_bridge_name">Liberty Bridge</string>
    <string name="liberty_bridge_description">The Liberty Bridge (Hun. <i>Szabadság Híd</i>) is a copper and stone construction finished in 1896, notable for the spires on each pylon sporting bronze statues of Turul, a bird spirit from Hungarian folklore often used as a symbol of Hungary.</string>
    <string name="fine_arts_museum_name">Museum of Fine Arts</string>
    <string name="fine_arts_museum_description">The Museum of Fine Arts (Hun. <i>Szépművészeti Múzeum</i>) is a epic neoclassical complex completed in 1906 located at Hero\'s Square in northeastern Pest, across from its sister museum, the Palace of Art.  While the Palace of Art is known for modern and contemporary work, the Museum of Fine Arts has an impressive collection of ancient, Medieval, and Renaissance art, including many works by Hungarian artists.</string>
    <string name="national_museum_name">Hungarian National Museum</string>
    <string name="national_museum_description">The Hungarian National Museum (Hun. <i>Magyar Nemzeti Múzeum</i>) is an imposing neoclassical structure in Pest built in the first half of the 19th century.  Primarily a historical museum, it contains many cultural and anthropological artifacts from prehistory up through the 20th century.</string>
    <string name="opera_house_name">Hungarian State Opera House</string>
    <string name="opera_house_description">Opera has thrived in Hungary for centuries, exemplified by the majestic neo-Renaissance State Opera House (Hun. <i>Magyar Állami Operaház</i>), which opened its sizable doors in 1884.  It plays host to hundreds of performances every year, drawing crowds of locals and tourists alike.</string>
    <string name="bartok_concert_hall_name">Béla Bartók National Concert Hall</string>
    <string name="bartok_concert_hall_description">The Palace of the Arts (Hun. <i>Művészetek Palotája</i>), or, as it is now called, Müpa Budapest, is a large, modern complex in the southern reaches of Pest full of various facilities for the arts, most notably the Bartók National Concert Hall.  Named after famed 20th century Hungarian composer and ethnomusicologist Béla Bartók, it is the largest performance hall in the city.  Contrary to most epic architecture in Budapest, which largely dates from the 19th or early 20th centuries, Müpa was finished in 2005, a testament to the city\'s ever-growing need for music performance space.</string>
    <string name="dohany_synagogue_name">Dohány Street Synagogue</string>
    <string name="dohany_synagogue_description">The Dohány Street Synagogue (Hun. <i>Dohány Utcai Zsinagóga</i>) is a 19th century synagogue built in an style heavily influenced Islamic architecture.  It is the largest synagogue in Europe, and it is not only an active house of worship, but also hosts a museum of Jewish religious and historical art and artifacts.</string>
    <string name="liberty_statue_name">Liberty Statue</string>
    <string name="liberty_statue_description">Liberty Statue, sometimes called Freedom Statue (Hun. <i>Szabadság-szobor</i>) is a monument on Gellért Hill in southern Buda, overlooking the city from on high.  Constructed shortly after World War II, it originally bore an inscription praising "Soviet heroes" who liberated Hungary from Nazi German occupation.  After the fall of the Soviet Union, the inscription was changed to simply praise all who "sacrificed their lives for the independence, freedom, and prosperity of Hungary."</string>
    <string name="buda_castle_name">Buda Castle</string>
    <string name="buda_castle_description">Buda Castle (Hun. <i>Budavári Palota</i>) is one of the oldest buildings in Hungary.  Built in 1265 on a hill in Buda overlooking the river, it was originally a palace for Hungarian royalty, though the structure has been largely rebuilt several times and played host to a variety of Hungarian (and sometimes Austrian) nobility.  Today, the structure is host to the National Széchényi Library (Hun. <i>Országos Széchényi Könyvtár</i>) and the Hungarian National Gallery (Hun. <i>Magyar Nemzeti Galéria</i>).  Apart from the fine collection of Medieval through Renaissance art in the gallery, the site itself has many fine sculptures and monuments.</string>
    <string name="liszt_academy_name">Franz Liszt Academy of Music</string>
    <string name="liszt_academy_description">Franz Liszt is the most famous Hungarian composer not from Hungary (he was raised in Austria and spoke no Hungarian), but he still managed to get an entire academy of music named after him (though not until after his death; it was originally simply the "College of Music").  The Franz List Academy of Music (Hun. <i>Liszt Ferenc Zeneművészeti Egyetem</i>) is a charming neo-Renaissance structure in the heart of Pest.  It is still an active conservatory, and has within it one of the many classical music concert spaces in Budapest.</string>
</resources>
